Welcome back to AM Northwest. Our first guest
knows how to spot a treasure even in a closet.
Here to help us find value in vintage clothing,
we welcome back antique appraiser Gary Germer.
Gary, good to see you. You too. So good to see
you. Okay, so you find things oftentimes at garage
sales and all
that, but this is more, this is really
looking for something of value in a closet.
In the closet. I
have to say handling estates as many as
we do and appraisals as many as we do,
one of the ways people
lose money is what's in the closet
or in the jewelry or in the clothing,
because it's a huge
multi-million dollar, multi-billion
dollar industry, the whole vintage.
Oh yeah, because there are whole
boutiques that sell vintage clothing, originals.
And the problem is, is there's a little bit
of a
disconnect, because when we were kids, well when
I was a kid, you're so much younger than me,
but when I...
Not the case, but okay. I'll
go with that. I'll take that.
When I was a kid, wearing hand-me-downs and
secondhand clothes meant you were poor. Right.
You went to Goodwill and you had, you
know, and... But now it's a thing.
And then it was about the 1980s is when
things started to shift and now collecting vintage
clothes or using vintage clothes has gotten
to be a big thing
with a younger generation. And so a lot of
people think if you're going to collect,
it's going to be worth
millions, you got to have something that was
hand-stitched by Coco Chanel or someone like that,
and you don't.
Right.
These three don't.
And the green dresses here, which my friend
Betsy at the Bliss House Museum loaned me,
are all different
vintages. The green dress is a 1950s party
dress. The two-piece Jackie Kennedy thing on the
end is more 1960s.
Right.
And the beaded one is a 1980s kind of reflection
back to the 20 kind of a flapper thing.
Oh, I can see that.
You know, and so people
will collect different eras.
So don't give it away.
Don't give it away. And look for...
And what you're looking for is this.
What you're looking for is color and
design and condition and quality of making.
By the 1980s into the 90s, there's a lot
of just fashion was almost throwaway.
You got clothes, you know, and
they were out of style right away.
And so these are all well-made. They can
be refitted back to a person who can,
you know, and can be altered to be used.
And so a lot of these you can reuse. So instead
of necessarily going out and spending enormous
monies for a fancy dress,
a dress like this one here, it's an Italian-made
dress, but this one, even though it has a good,
nice label in it,
you're looking at about $200 out of
boutique is about where you're at.
And maybe $100 on this one, $100, $150 on this
one, and a $2, $250, maybe $3 on the two-piece
on the end is what the
retail end of it would be.
If you're going to try to sell it, what you got
to look for, too, is also how clean and if it
needs to be pressed, that sort of thing.
Yeah, that makes sense.
Now, shoes and purses.
People collect, and I have
a collection of stuff here.
These are incredible.
Aren't those fun? Alligator?
Yeah.
Yeah, and I have no problem personally
with killing alligators, but that's me.
I don't personally do it, but, you know.
Whereas furs are another matter.
People don't, to try to sell a
mink coat is next to impossible.
Yeah, you can't do that.
Fake fur is huge.
Right.
So if you find the fake fur. People
will also collect subcategories.
Some want all of it. Some collect
purses and shoes. Some collect...
Yeah, the beaded.
The beaded purses I love.
Aren't those fun?
Yeah.
Those are really fun.
And what's fun about it is you can find a nice
little beaded purse like that if you needed something
to go out.
You know, you're going out on
an event and you wanted it.
You can find them for like
25, 30 bucks in a shop.
They're not hugely expensive.
One of the things they also
lose money on is jewelry.
Okay.
And I have people bring me to my office.
They're dealing with grandma's
house, and they have the jewelry box.
And...
Invariably, the first
thing I look for is gold.
Right.
Is there any gold? And it will
sift the gold and silver out.
And then you're looking at names.
And so like these are a good
example. These three here.
We found at an estate that was going
to be... They were in the dollar box.
And this two-piece set is Tiffany.
Oh.
In sterling. And so it's real simple.
Yeah.
It's easy to... But on a
secondary market, it's $200.
Mexican silver is really big.
Oh.
And so in the 20s, 30s, 40s, 50s.
Wow.
You could go to Mexico and buy in the Taxco
silver regions silver fairly inexpensively.
Yeah.
And now a necklace like that, it's a
secondary maker, but it's a good piece.
It's about, you know, $400 for that.
I see.
And then this one here. I don't
know if they can see it. Sorry.
Oh, sorry about that.
I got it. That's fine.
Okay.
And then the gold...
And then this one, George Jensen.
Oh.
Which is one that they found for a
dollar. And this is a Danish designer.
And that's another $400
necklace we found for a dollar.
These are super pretty too.
And aren't those fun?
Yeah.
So finding, again, costume jewelry.
Yep.
And that isn't saying there isn't a
lot of plastic pop beads and stuff.
Sure. Sure.
It's just pure junk.
What you're looking for on your costume
jewelry are some of the bigger names.
And now is a good time to buy it.
It's got a big craze and there's
a lot of it on the market.
Yeah, you're right.
So the prices have
actually come down a lot.
Okay.
And so you can collect, find really
wonderful things on a secondary market.
And of course, hats have
always been popular.
And big brimmed hats are
really, really great.
But any...
Any hats are collected.
Things people don't want.
Mink coats.
Right.
Wedding dresses.
Oh, yeah.
And brooches.
And I don't...pins.
Broaches, yeah.
I don't know why.
Pins are, to me, like wearing
a little piece of art.
Yeah.
But...
People...I have a certain...
You have to repurpose them.
Gary, thank you so much.
Lots of valuable information.